Okay, in the last video you saw that
object dstructuring was a thing. So that
might lead you to ask, can you spread an
object? And you in fact can because
objects just like arrays um your
variable here is not storing the actual
object. It's actually just storing uh
information about where the actual
object is. So that means if I created a
second object called Batman 2 and set it
equal to Batman and then made a change
to Batman
um
suddenly that would change Batman 2
because Batman 2 isn't holding the
actual object right here. It's just
holding a location where that actual
object is. So when I change the actual
object, it changes the actual object.
And since both Batman and Batman 2 are
pointing to the same object, only one
thing has been changed.
Um,
okay. So, how do we get around this?
Well, the way we get around this is we
can say let Batman 2 equal and then we
create a new object. And it'd be a pain
just like when we were creating a new
array. So if we said let Batman 3 equal
a new array where we'd have to copy in
by hand all of the numbers that would
kind of suck. So what we can do is we
can use the same spread operator we used
with arrays we can use it with objects.
So I can say dot dot dot Batman. So what
I'm saying is create a new object here.
Take all of the things inside of the old
object and copy them into this new
object. Spread them out. Now we have a
new object called Batman 2.
And then what I'm going to do is on the
next line I'm going to say Batman do
first name equals hello.
So when I run this through the code,
it's going to create one object and
store it in Batman. And it's going to
create another object and copy in the
attributes from the first object. then
it's going to change the first object
and we'll go to that point. So we'll
save it and we'll come over here
and we'll come to our sources
and we'll click on script.js and we're
going to put a break point right on this
line. So if we reload our page, it
pauses. We're about to create our Batman
variable. If we hit next and we hover
over Batman, we can see the alias is
Batman. First name is Bruce, last name
is Wayne. Numb villains caught is 20.
If we hit If we hover over Batman 2, it
has not been created yet. If we hit
next, it spreads out Batman into Batman
2. And when we hover over Batman 2, it
has an alias of Batman, a first name of
Bruce, a last name of Waynees, and
number of villains caught equal to 20.
If we hit the next button, we just
adjusted the first object. So now his
alias is Batman. His first name is
hello.
Let's look at Batman 2. His first name
is still Bruce. That is because these
are two different objects. We created an
object using the two curly braces and
then we said copy these attributes into
this object. Once you've done that,
change the first object. So that's cool.
Um, but what if we wanted to copy all of
the attributes with one slight
adjustment? So, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to create Batman 2. But in
addition to copying all of these
attributes, I want to give him a new
attribute and I'm going to call it
vehicle. And I'm going to store
Batmobile.
So, if I save this
and I come over here
then and I reload.
Oops, sorry. Reload with a break point.
So, I'm going to put a breakpoint here.
Reload. It pauses. We create the Batman
variable. The Batman variable, four
attributes. You've seen them enough
times. I'm not going to read them again.
I'm going to hit next. We're about to
create Batman 2 by putting in everything
from Batman and then creating a new key
called vehicle and storing Batmobile.
So, if we hit next and hover over Batman
2, it has all of the four attributes we
previously had plus a new attribute
called vehicle that's storing Batmobile.
So when you are using this spread
operator, you don't have to just
directly copy the object. You can
directly copy the object and then make a
change to it. And that concludes this
video on changing with object
destructuring.